Guide to the Boris Filippov Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1946-1969; I,; 4; (10 boxes)
  - Vanderbilt University, 1967-68 (Box 10, Folder 276)
  - Vasilov, B. I., 1962-68, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 277)
  - Veidle, V., 1965-66 (Box 10, Folder 278)
    [Also known as Wladimir Weidlé]
  - Viktorov, P. V., 1964-69 (Box 10, Folder 279)
  - Vlach, Robert, 1961-65 (Box 10, Folder 280)
    See also: Books Abroad, folder 40
  - Vodov, S. A., 1962-67 (Box 10, Folder 281)
    Includes: La pensée russe
  - Vol'skaia, V. N., 1965-67 (Box 10, Folder 282)
  - Voss, Eugen, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 283)
  - "W" General, 1966-67 (Box 10, Folder 284)
  - Walden Press, 1966-67 (Box 10, Folder 285)
    Includes A. Donat
  - Weiner, Jack, 1964-69 (Box 10, Folder 286)
    [Also spelled IA. Veiner]
  - Wetter, Gustav, 1968 Dec 12 (Box 10, Folder 287)
  - Wiren-Garczynski, Vera von, 1965-67, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 288)
  - "Y-Z" General, 1956-64 (Box 10, Folder 289)
  - Zabezhinskii, Grigorii, 1963-65, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 290)
  - Zaitsev, Boris, 1963-69 (Box 10, Folder 291-292)
  - Zamoyska, Helène, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 293)
  - Zenkovsky, Serge, 1967-69 (Box 10, Folder 294)
  - Zhukov, IA. D., 1964-69 (Box 10, Folder 295)
    [Also spelled Joukov]
  - Znosko-Borovskii, Mitrofan, Father, 1958-69 (Box 10, Folder 296)
- Writings by B. A. Filippov, 1944-1968; II,; 0.8; (2 boxes)
  - BOOKS
    - Tuskloe okontse, page proofs, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 297)
    - Veter svezheet
      - Typescript, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 298)
      - Typescript carbon, 2 copies, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 299)
      - "V stepi," typescript, corrected, 1967 Dec 4 (Box 11, Folder 300)
      - "Nichego osobennogo", "V taige," typescript, carbon, corrected, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 301)
    - Vsegda sovremenniki: Literaturnye ocherki
      - Title page and introduction, partial typescript, corrected, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 302)
      - "Useknovennaia glava," page proofs, corrected, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 303)
      - "Poet vsednevnosti (Vladislav Khodasevich)," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 304)
    - Vstrechnye v doroge: povesti i ocherki
      - Typescript, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 305-315)
      - Typescript carbon, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 316-325)
  - SHORTER WORKS
    - "A nebo budushchim beremenno," typescript, corrected, plus 2 carbon copies, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 326)
      Re: Osip Mandel'shtam
    - "Anna Akhmatova," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 327)
    - "Chesnochek," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 328)
    - "IAvlenie," typescript, corrected, plus 2 carbon copies, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 329)
    - "Iosif Brodskii," typescript, carbon, photostats of poems, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 330)
    - "IUnost': liricheskii chertopolokh v proze i stikhakh," typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 331)
    - "Kontsert," typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 332)
    - "Leningrad: vtoroi liricheskii cherto- polokh v proze i stikhakh," typescript and typescript, carbon, 1946 Nov 24 (Box 12, Folder 333)
    - "Opal'noe proizvedenie," typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 334)
      Re: Mikhail Zoshchenko
    - "O proekte 'Istorii russkoi filosofskoi mysli v russkoi literature'"
      - Typescript and carbon (Box 12, Folder 335)
      - Typescript, carbon, corrected, 2 copies, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 336)
      - Typescript, carbon, corrected, 2 copies, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 337)
    - "O proze Pasternaka," typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 338)
    - "Opyt bibliografii litertury po istorii russkoi arkhitektury," typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 339)
    - "O rodine," typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 340)
    - "O veshchakh," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 341)
    - "Po povodu i bez povoda," typescript, carbon fragments, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 342)
    - "Revoliutsiia i intelligentsiia v SSSR," typescript, carbon (3 copies), with holograph notations, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 343)
    - "Rifmovannye dogadki"
      Re: Dmitrii I. Klenovskii
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 344)
      - Typescript and carbon (Box 12, Folder 345)
    - "Surovyi sputnik," typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 346)
    - "'Svecha gorela na stole'," typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 347)
      Re: Boris Pasternak
    - "Usy," typescript, carbon, 2 copies, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 348)
    - "Vol'pin," typescript, plus 2 carbon copies, and materials relating to Vol'pin's Mgnovennoe izlozhenie moikh filosofskikh vzgliadov (Box 12, Folder 349)
    - Poems, typescript, carbon, 1944-53 (Box 12, Folder 350)
    - Untitled typescript re: painting, with carbon, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 351)
    - Untitled typescript, carbon, re: the Russian intelligentsia, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 352)
- Books edited by B. A. Filippov, 1908-1967; III,; 2; (5 boxes)
  - AKHMATOVA, ANNA ANDREEVNA. SOBRANIE SOCHINENII
    - Akhmatova, Anna
      - "Argonavty," typescript and 2 carbons (Box 13, Folder 353)
      - "Poema bez geroia"
        - Photostat and typescript carbon of journal publication (Box 13, Folder 354)
        - Typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 355)
        - Typescript plus 2 carbon copies, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 356)
      - "Shag vremeni," typescript plus 3 carbons, with holograph notations, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 357)
      - Articles, typescript, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 358)
      - Poems and notes, typescript, carbons and holograph (Box 13, Folder 359)
    - Filippov, Boris
      "Poema bez geroia" (article)
      - Typescript, some leaves carbons, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 360)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 361)
      - Holograph notes on A. A. Akhmatova (Box 13, Folder 362)
    - Other editorial materials
      - Biographical note, typescript, carbon, 1964 Jun 28 (Box 13, Folder 363)
      - "Iz vospominanii ob Anne Akhmatovoi," typescript, plus 2 carbon copies, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 364)
      - Miscellaneous editorial materials, typescript, photostat, holograph, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 365)
      - Memorandum from The New York Public Library re: Akhmatova exhibition, typescript, 1966 Mar 29 (Box 13, Folder 366)
  - AKHMATOVA, ANNA. REQUIEM.
    With Estonian translation by Maria Under.
    - Notes by B. A. Filippov and A. Rannit, ALS to Filippov from Rannit, and copies of correspondence between A. A. Akhmatova and A. Rannit, typescripts, annotated, 1962, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 367)
    - Galley proofs, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 368)
    - Page proofs, bound, annotated (Box 13, Folder 369)
  - DANILEVSKII, N. IA. ROSSIIA I EVROPA
    - Ivask, IUrii, "Filosofiia istorii Danilevskogo v knige Rossiia i Evropa"
      - Typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 370)
      - Typescript, carbon, corrected, pasted, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 371)
  - GUMILEV, NIKOLAI. SOBRANIE SOCHINENII
    - Gumilev, Nikolai
      - "Chitatel'," typescript and carbon (Box 13, Folder 372)
      - "Tri novelly. Radosti zemnoi liubvi," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 373-374)
      - "Tri novelly. Radosti zemnoi liubvi," typescript, carbon, corrected (2 copies), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 375-376)
      - "Veselye brat'ia: povest'," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 377)
      - "Vstuplenie," typescript, carbon, re: Aleksey Konstantinovich Tolstoy, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 378)
    - Filippov, Boris
      - Holograph notes, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 379)
  - KANDINSKY, WASSILY. DUKHOVNOE V ISKUSSTVE
    - Kandinsky, Wassily
      - Partial typescript, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 380-381)
      - Typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 382-383)
      - Typescript, annotated, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 384-385)
      - Typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 386)
    - Other editorial materials
      - "Predislovie," typescript and 2 carbons (Box 14, Folder 387)
      - "Predislovie," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 388)
    - Book drafts
      - Page proofs, fragment, 1967 Mar 29 (Box 14, Folder 389)
  - KLIUEV, NIKOLAI ALEKSEEVICH. SOBRANIE SOCHINENII
    - Filippov, Boris
      - Bibliography, typescript, carbon, corrected (2 copies), n.d. (Box 14, Folder 390)
    - Book drafts
      - Page proofs, corrected, with typescript additions, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 391-398)
      - Page proofs, corrected, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 399-402)
  - LIKI ROSSII: ANTOLOGIIA RUSSKOI POEZIIA
    - Bound typescript (Box 15, Folder 403)
  - MANDEL'SHTAM, OSIP. SOBRANIE SOCHINENII
    - Mandel'shtam, Osip
      Poems
      - "Armeniia," photocopies, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 404)
      - "Stikhotvoreniia," typescript, carbon, with holograph notations, 1913-25 (Box 15, Folder 405)
      - Various poems, photocopies, 1966, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 406)
      - Various poems, typescript, carbon, 1917-18 (Box 15, Folder 407)
      - Various poems, typescript, photostat of holograph, 1908-34 (Box 15, Folder 408)
      - Various poems, typescript, carbon with holograph notations, 1913-16 (Box 15, Folder 409)
      - Various poems, holograph and typescript, 1909-34 (Box 15, Folder 410)
      - Zvezda Vostoka, entire issue of journal (no. 3), photocopy, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 411-413)
      - Prose works
        - "Dante," typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 414)
        - "Deviatnadtsatyi vek," typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 415)
        - "Dva pis'ma," typescript and copy (Box 15, Folder 416)
        - "Gumanizm i sovremennost'," photostat, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 417)
        - "Osip Mandel'shtam o khristianskom iskusstve," entire issue of La pensée russe, 1963 Nov 28 (Box 15, Folder 418)
        - "Pis'ma v redaktsiiu," 1915-29, typescript and carbon (Box 15, Folder 419)
        - "Pushkin i Skriabin," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 420)
        - "Stat'i o perevodakh," typescript carbon, 1929 (Box 15, Folder 421)
        - "Stat'i o perevodakh," typescript carbon and fragment, 1929 (Box 15, Folder 422)
        - "Utro akmeizma," photo print copy, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 423)
        - Fragments, typescript, corrected, 1916-38 (Box 15, Folder 424)
    - Filippov, Boris
      - Commentary, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 425)
      - Commentary, typescript and carbon (Box 16, Folder 426)
      - TLS from Gleb Struve and Clarence Brown, typescript, 1965-67 (Box 16, Folder 427)
      - Bibliography, typescript and holograph (Box 16, Folder 428)
    - Other editorial materials
      - Koriakov, M. "Listki iz bloknota," entire issue of Novoe russkoe slovo, 1967 Nov 19 (Box 16, Folder 429)
      - Rais, E. "Tvorchestvo Osipa Mandel'shtama," holograph and typescript, 1963 Dec 21 (Box 16, Folder 430)
      - Rozhdestvenskii, V. Typescript, carbon with holograph notes, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 431)
      - Struve, Gleb. "Dnevnik chitatelia," Photocopy, 1961 May 25 (Box 16, Folder 432)
      - Tager, E. M. "O Mandel'shtame," galley proofs from Novyi zhurnal (Box 16, Folder 433)
      - Tarkovskii, Arsenii Aleksandrovich. [Poems], typescript, carbon, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 434)
      - "Sud'ba Mandel'shtama," photostat of typescript (Box 16, Folder 435)
      - References to A. A. Akhmatova and O. E. Mandel'shtama, typescript (Box 16, Folder 436)
    - Book drafts
      - Volume 3, partial typescript, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 437)
      - Page proofs, with holograph annotations, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 438-446)
  - TERTS, ABRAM. FANTASTICHESKII MIR ABRAMA TERTSA
    Pseudonym of Andrei Donat'evich Siniavskii
    - Terts, "Chto takoe sotsialisticheskii realizm?"
      - Typescript with holograph addition, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 447)
      - Photo print copy of typescript in folder 447 (Box 17, Folder 448)
      - Other editorial materials: "Sud nad A. D. Siniavskim i IU. M. Danielem," typescript, carbon, 1966 Feb 14 (Box 17, Folder 449)
  - ZOSHCHENKO, MIKHAIL. PERED VOSKHODOM SOLNTSA
    - Zoshchenko, Mikhail
      - "Pered voskhodom solntsa," photocopy of journal publication, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 450)
    - Vera von Wiren-Garczynski
      "Mikhail Zoshchenko -- Avtor psikhoanaliticheskikh povestei"
      - Typescript in English under title "Healing and Psychics", corrected (Box 17, Folder 451)
      - Typescript in English under title "Healing and Psychics", corrected (Box 17, Folder 452)
      - Typescript, carbon, annotated, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 453)
      - Typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 454)
      - Page proofs, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 455-456)
- Writings of Others, 1927-1967; IV,; 0.8; (2 boxes)
  - Anisimov, Oleg. "Rol' Rossii v mirovom progresse," typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 457)
  - Arbatov, A. [pseudonym], "Nishcheta, Privychki, Pravda"
    - Photocopy of typescript, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 458)
    - English translation with introduction by Christopher Bird, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 459)
  - Bilimovich, A. D. "Ekonomicheskii stroi poslebol'shevistskoi Rossii," typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 460)
  - Bogdanov, Leonid [pseudonym]
    - "Beda s Antonom," typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 461)
    - "Bedovaia zhist'," typescript, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 462)
    - "Bedovaia zhist': poema v proze. Prodolzhenie 1-e," typescript, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 463)
    - "Bedovaia zhist': poema v proze. Prodolzhenie 2-e," typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 464)
    - "Bedovaia zhist': poema v proze. Okonchanie," typescript, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 465)
    - "Bez illiuzii," typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 466)
    - "Biriuzovye vy kolechki," typescript, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 467)
    - "Biust," typescript and carbon (Box 18, Folder 468)
    - "Blagodetel'," typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 18, Folder 469)
    - "Daleko ot Moskvy i Vashingtona (satiricheskaia skazka)," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 470)
    - "Dogonim i peregonim," typescript and carbon (Box 18, Folder 471)
    - "Gangstery," typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 472)
    - "Grustno," typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 473)
    - "Kto poslednii?... Ia za vami," typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 474)
    - "Malye zemli," Typescript carbon, typescript, fragments, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 475)
      Includes ALS from Isaac Don Levine to L. Bogdan dated 1955 May 9
    - "Malye zemil," typescript carbon, 2 copies, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 476)
    - "Matiusha," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 477)
    - "Matiusha," typescript and carbon (Box 18, Folder 478)
    - "Mirazh," typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 479)
    - "Muchitel'," typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 480)
    - "Nado uchit'sia," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 481)
    - "Nikolen'ka," typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 482)
    - "Peremeshchennoe litso Pustiak. Literaturnyi stsenarii," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 483)
    - "Pod razvesistoi lipoi," typescript carbon, 1954 (Box 18, Folder 484)
    - "Prostoi retsept," typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 485)
    - "Ramka," typescript, carbon, 2 copies, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 486)
    - "Rodstvenniki," typescript and 2 carbons (Box 18, Folder 487)
    - "S''ezd i ego itogi," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 488)
    - "Smeiushchiisia posol. Sovremennaia skazka dlia detei i vzroslykh," typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 489)
    - "Sobaka drug cheloveka?," typescript and carbon (Box 18, Folder 490)
    - "Sobaka drug cheloveka?," 2 typescript carbons, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 491)
    - "Trubka: satiricheskaia povest'," typescript, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 492)
    - "Uchit'sia nado," typescript and carbon (Box 18, Folder 493)
    - "Utrennee kofe," typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 494)
    - "V storone ot bol'shoi dorogi," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 495)
    - "Za Stalina," typescript, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 496)
    - "Zashchitnik," typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 497)
    - Untitled, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 498)
  - Bondarenko, V. "Veka i desiatiletiia," page proofs, corrected (Box 19, Folder 499)
  - Butkov, V.
    - "49 let kommunisticheskogo vladychestva," typescript, mimeograph, 1966 Nov 6 (Box 19, Folder 500)
    - "Odinnadtsat' vekov rossiiskogo gosudarstva," typescript, mimeograph (Box 19, Folder 501)
  - Egunov, Aleksandr Nikolaevich. Poems, "Rugatel'naia stat'ia," holograph, with ALS to Boris Filippov dated 1944 Dec 29, 1927-44 (Box 19, Folder 502)
  - IUrova, O.
    - "Istoriia odnogo prestupleniia," typescript, carbon, 2 copies, 1946-47 (Box 19, Folder 503)
    - "Noch' pod sed'moe noiabria," typescript and carbon, 1946 (Box 19, Folder 504)
  - Kotlin, A.
    See: Egunov, Aleksandr Nikolaevich, box 10, folder 502
  - Krugovoi, G.
    - "Puti dukhovnogo razvitiia natsii v ego sotsial'nom aspekte," typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 505)
    - "Protsessy v srede molodezhi," typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 506)
    - Untitled, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 507)
  - Martynov, Leonid. "Nad volnami, nad moriami," typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 508)
  - Meier, Georgii. Svet v nochi. (O "Prestuplenii i nakazanii"). Opyt medlennogo chteniia, page proofs, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 509-514)
  - Mikhailovskii, V. "Vstrecha," typescript, carbon, 1944 (Box 19, Folder 515)
  - Muromtsev, S. [Poems], typescript, 1943 (Box 19, Folder 516)
  - Neizvestnyi, Ernst. "Otkryvat' novoe." Typescript, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 516a)
  - Nikolev, Andrei. "Stikhi," typescript, bound in folder (Box 19, Folder 517)
  - Pil'skii, P. "Andrei Belyi," holograph (Box 19, Folder 518)
  - Parfenov, A. "Ognennyi zmii," typescript bound in folder, 1947 (Box 19, Folder 519)
  - Ponomarev, Vasilii. "IAzycheskie moleniia v novgorodskoi zemle," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 520)
  - Serafimovskii listok, entire issues 1 and 2, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 521)
  - Stranoliubskii, Petr
    - "V predelax vozmozhnogo," 3 typescripts, 1946 Nov 24 (Box 19, Folder 522)
    - "Tkan' zhizni," 4 typescripts, 1946 Oct 23 (Box 19, Folder 523)
  - Tarsis, Valerii. "Palata no. 7," photocopy of typescript, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 524)
  - Ul'ianov, N. "Natsional'nyi vopros," typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 525)
- Book-Cover Art by Serge Hollerbach, 1965-1966; V,; 0.4; (1 box)
  - Adamovich, Georgii. Edinstvo. Annotated by G. Adamovich, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 526)
  - Akhmatova, Anna. With an Estonian translation by Marie Under. Requiem. (Box 20, Folder 527)
  - Annenkov, IUrii. Dnevnik moikh vstrech., n.d (Box 20, Folder 528)
    See also: Box 1, folder 13-17
  - Arzhak, Nikolai Govorit Moskva, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 529)
  - Brodskii, Iosif. Stikhotvoreniia, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 530)
  - Chasy, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 531)
  - Filippov, Boris
    - Chetyre knigi: stikhi 1941-1962, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 532)
    - Tuskloe okontse, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 533)
    - Veter svezheet, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 534)
  - Frank, S. L. Iz istorii russkoi filosofskoi mysli kontsa 19-go i nachala 20-go veka: Antologiia, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 535)
  - Inter-Language Literary Associates
    - Katalog, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 536)
    - Catalogue/Katalog, 1965-66 (Box 20, Folder 537)
  - Kliuev, Nikolai Sochineniia, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 538)
  - Samarin, Vladimir. Teni na stene, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 539)
  - Terts, Abram
    - Fantasticheskii mir Abrama Tertsa, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 540)
    - Mysli vrasplokh, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 541)
  - Voloshin, Maksimilian. Stikhotvoreniia, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 542)
  - Zaitsev, Boris. Reka vremeni, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 543)
  - Zamiatin, Evgenii.
    - Litsa, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 544)
    - My, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 545)
    - Povesti i rasskazy, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 546)
    - Sochineniia, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 547)
  - Zoshchenko, Mikhail. Pered voskhodom solntsa, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 548)
- Restricted Fragile, 0.25; (1 box)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 21, Restricted Fragile Papers, contains fragile originals. The material is arranged in folder order and may only be seen with the permission of the appropriate curator. Preservation photocopies have been placed in the main files for reference use.
  - Box 1, folder 23 (Box 21, Folder 549)
  - Box 3, folder 78 (Box 21, Folder 550)
  - Box 7, folder 219 (Box 21, Folder 551)
  - Box 12, folder 341 (Box 21, Folder 552)
  - Box 16, folder 436 (Box 21, Folder 553)